<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<Project>
  <Information>
    <Menu>
      <ul>
<li><a href="index.html">Versions</a>
<ul>
<li><a href="../1.2.5/index.html">1.2.5 (Latest)</a></li>
<li><a href="../1.2.4/index.html">1.2.4</a></li>
<li><a href="../1.2.2/index.html">1.2.3 - 1.2.2</a></li>
<li><a href="../1.2.1/index.html">1.2.1</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="changelog.html">Changelog</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.doctran.co.uk">Doctran Home</a></li>
</ul>
</Menu>
    <UserPage>
      <Path>.\changelog.html</Path>
      <Content>
        <h1>Changelog</h1>

<h2>Version 1.2.5 (Latest)</h2>

<ul>
<li>Updated syntax highlighter to be more accurate, aware of more language features and copy-and-paste friendly.</li>
<li>The option <code>--time-run</code> has been added to specify that performance timings should be saved within an XML file in the xml directory of the output directory.</li>
<li>Stopped the output of unneeded files when creating static wiki documentation (documentation containing no Fortran source files).</li>
<li>In tables and menu lists one can use <code>Program</code> as a <code>TYPE_VALUE</code> to output a table or list of Fortran programs.</li>
<li>A button to toggle the visibility of the menu has been added to documentation generated.</li>
<li>Stopped broken links occurring within search results.</li>
<li>Fixed some problems with the menu's display on the Chrome browser.</li>
<li>Fixed some problems with the menu's display on the Firefox browser on Ubuntu.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Version 1.2.4</h2>

<ul>
<li>Errors messages are displayed for structural issues in the code.</li>
<li>The option <code>--save_xml=PATH</code> has been changed to <code>--save-xmls</code>. The appearance of this option now instructs the program to save the XMLs generated to a directory called <code>xml</code> within the output directory.</li>
<li>The option <code>--no-output</code> has been added. The appearance of this option instructs the program not to generate any documentation. If <code>--save-xmls</code> appears, XML data will still be saved.</li>
<li>The options <code>--project_file</code> has been changed to <code>--project-file</code>.</li>
<li>The font of syntax highlighted code has been changed to monospace to an issue with misaligned characters.</li>
<li>Initializations are now shown for variables.</li>
<li>Fixed bug which caused procedure arguments not to be shown in call syntax argument lists.</li>
<li>Fixed bug causing inheritance hierarchy to be display in reverse.</li>
<li>Fixed some issues with array descriptions.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Version 1.2.3</h2>

<ul>
<li>Improved error messages.</li>
<li>Fixed bug causing block description heading sections to not be collapsible.</li>
<li>Fixed broken links in procedure argument documentation.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Version 1.2.2</h2>

<ul>
<li>The style of the generated documentation has been modified to take advantage of wide screen and high resolution displays.</li>
<li><code>Menu</code> project information added, to allow menu customizations. The menu is now generated from a markdown or HTML file containing macros.</li>
<li><code>UserPage</code> project information added, so that additional documentation pages can be created from the user's markdown or HTML files.</li>
<li><code>Source</code> project information added so that source files can be specified from the project file.</li>
<li>A project page is no longer automatically generated from comments within the project file, instead this can be created using the <code>UserPage</code> information.</li>
<li><code>Tagline</code> project information added, which should not be used to specify the project's tagline.</li>
<li>Color schemes removed.</li>
<li><code>--color_scheme</code> command-line argument removed.</li>
<li><code>--theme</code> command line argument removed.</li>
<li>Doctran will now run without any Fortran source files specified, to allow for use as a static wiki generator.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Version 1.2.1</h2>

<ul>
<li>The block searching algorithm has been improved.</li>
<li>The "end" statement to terminate functions and subroutines within interfaces is now reconsigned.</li>
<li>Broken links in the 'Type' column of argument lists within the documentation pages of assignments and operators fixed.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Version 1.2</h2>

<ul>
<li>Support for the object oriented constructs from the Fortran 2003 standard added.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Version 1.1</h2>

<ul>
<li>Markdown supported within descriptions added.</li>
<li>Syntax highlighting of source code added.</li>
<li>A Javascript search added.</li>
<li>Support for different color schemes.</li>
</ul>

<h2>Version 1.0</h2>

<ul>
<li>Initial Release </li>
</ul>
</Content>
    </UserPage>
    <UserPage>
      <Path>.\index.html</Path>
      <Content>
        <h1>Version Catalogue</h1>

<p><image align="left" style="margin: 0 4em 1.0em 0" src="images/logo.png" />
Previous versions of Doctran are listed below.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="../1.2.5/index.md">1.2.5</a> (Latest)</li>
<li><a href="../1.2.4/index.md">1.2.4</a></li>
<li><a href="../1.2.2/index.md">1.2.3 - 1.2.2</a></li>
<li><a href="../1.2.1/index.md">1.2.1</a></li>
</ul>
</Content>
    </UserPage>
    <Name>Doctran</Name>
  </Information>
  <DocCreated>
    <DateTime>2016-04-20T15:30:23.5346474+01:00</DateTime>
  </DocCreated>
  <Files />
</Project>